SUREN ALE



- 9868114024
- surenale10@gmail.com
- O Chyasal-9, Lalitpur
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/suren-ale-a8a037213/
- https://github.com/surenale

SUMMARY

Hi i am a computer engineering student currently pass out from Himalaya College of Engineering. I am flexible, reliable, enthusiastic, self-motivated, hard working responsible person and can able to cope with different situation. Being a computer engineering student I eagerly want to gain more hands on experience on projects based on real world scenario.

SKILLS

- Good Communication Skills
- Computer Skills
- Problem solving skills
- Team Work
- Ability to cope with different situation

LANGUAGE

Nepali			
English			
Magar			

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Computer Engineering

Himalaya College Of Engineering / lalitpur-9 / May, 2018 - May, 2022

EXPERIENCE

Android Application Development

January, 2022 - June, 2022

Stack used :-

- Build.gradle:- code compilation, testing, running app on device.
- Components:-activities, services, content providers.
- AndroidManifest.xml:-permissions,activity,meta-data.
- Resources:-drawable,layout,values.

Web Development

January, 2022 - January, 2022

- Languages :-HTML,CSS,JavaScript and Node.
- Stack used:-Express, Routing, Partials, API, NPM, Handlebars, Static path.

Tools and Technologies

January, 2022 - January, 2022

I have basic knowledge on these listed below tools and technologies.

- 1. Intermediate knowledge on Git & Github
- 2. OS -> Intermediate understanding on Linux(Ubuntu), Windows.
- 3. Flexible with CLI/Linux terminal.

Programming Languages

January, 2022 - January, 2022

I have experienced on these mentioned language C, C++, JAVA, Javascript and Node.

PROJECTS

Women Safety App

This project is for the purpose of safety to the women from being violence. The main objective of this project is to help women when she feels danger in situation by call and sending the location using GPS through easy mobile application. The workflow describe that if given app button is hold for 5 second then it automatically call to parents/belongings and send location so that parents can immediately take action finding the location and call. My role to this project is i have done front-end and back-end.

https://github.com/surenale/WomenSafetyApp

Dynamic Weather WebApp

The main purpose of this Web App is to get the current weather condition and temperature of any cities across the world. When the user wants to know the weather condition of any cities and hit search, it simply fetch API from openWeather service dynamically and then Web App provide the weather condition to the user.

https://github.com/surenale/WeatherApp

RestFulAPI

This is the project of simple CRUD operation of student registration using the HTTP methods called as POST,READ, PUT/PATCH and DELETE. In this project , I have used Node and it's framework express for routing and for HTTP methods. Mongoose for database connection and schema definition and mongoDB database for students registration.

https://github.com/surenale/restfulApi